<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Code Privy]]></title>
  <link href="http://joeltaylor.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://joeltaylor.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T23:04:14+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://joeltaylor.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joel Taylor]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basis of the Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeltaylor.github.io/blog/2014/05/06/the-causation-of-blogging/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-06T21:27:29+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeltaylor.github.io/blog/2014/05/06/the-causation-of-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I started my first development job, I was advised by another developer to
start a blog and document what I was learning. At the time, it seemed like a novel
idea but it wasn&#8217;t exactly pertinent to my scenario. Being new to development, most
of my time was spent in a chaotic bustle to absorb as much content as possible.
I have two reasons for blogging &#8211; one personal and the other community oriented. First,
writing has always been a vehicle to better process my thoughts. Second, I&#8217;ve benefited
from the blogs of other developers on numerous occasions and want to give back.
I&#8217;ll explain.</p>




<p>It&#8217;s been said numerous times that you don&#8217;t really know something unless you
can effectively teach it. I&#8217;m not aiming to write an introductory course to Ruby
but I do hope to share knowledge and challenge myself to understand all the components
enough to explain them thoroughly. As much as I like being able to copy and paste
a solution from Stack Overflow, in the end, it&#8217;s much more beneficial to understand
why things work the way they do. Writing is a form of processing that takes all
my scattered thoughts and makes them coherent. It&#8217;s my hope the blog will serve
as a resource to improve my understanding as I progress.</p>




<p>Recently, I sat down to get started on a freshly cloned Rails project and
couldn&#8217;t get the project&#8217;s gems to install. Some foreign error wasn&#8217;t allowing me
to proceed and I spent roughly 2 hours trying all sorts of debugging.
After swallowing my pride, I ran to Google with the error and found that other
developers had experienced, as well as solved, the error I was burdened by.
Point blank, I benefit from the thoughts and knowledge of other developers and
feel inclined to give back. In a sense, it&#8217;s my way of giving back to the
community so that it can continue to be furthered and improved.</p>




<p>With that said, I hope my code snippets can save someone else some time as
well as increase my understanding of the code at hand. </p>




<p>Here&#8217;s to better coding.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
