<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vagrant | Code Privy]]></title>
  <link href="http://codeprivy.com/blog/categories/vagrant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://codeprivy.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-15T15:25:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://codeprivy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joel Taylor]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capybara and Vagrant]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeprivy.com/blog/2014/07/13/capybara-and-vagrant/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T20:22:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://codeprivy.com/blog/2014/07/13/capybara-and-vagrant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here's a quick-tip for Vagrant users:</p>




<p>One of my favorite tools that Capybara has to offer is <code>save_and_open_page</code>
for those times when you're left wondering where exactly your fictional user ended up.
Unfortunately, when using a VM without a GUI, there's no browser to open the page in.
</p>




<p>Luckily, there's a really simple workaround. In your test helper add
<code>Capybara.save_and_open_page_path = "/vagrant/debug_pages"</code> and the
page will now be saved as HTML in your /vagrant directory. Of course, you can name
the holding directory anything you want. In your tests you'll  need to use <code>save_page</code>
to avoid the browser error and find the page saved in your specified directory.</p>




<p>Keep on keeping vagrant up.</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails With Vagrant]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeprivy.com/blog/2014/07/01/rails-with-vagrant/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-01T12:09:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://codeprivy.com/blog/2014/07/01/rails-with-vagrant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Vagrant makes setting up a development environment simple. Even more, the environments
can be shared to reduce any compatibility issues with a user's personal setup.
More often than not, when I clone a project, I have to spend a good deal of time
getting all the components of a project to work with my setup. I'm a fan of cloning
a project, running <code>vagrant up</code> and getting started immediately. Vagrant
is the golden sandbox that has me a bit too thrilled.</p>




<p>The folks at JumpstartLab put out an excellent
<a href="http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/topics/vagrant_setup.html">tutorial</a> on
getting Vagrant setup with all the basic necessities. One issue I continued to run
into though was a language error with Postgres when trying to run
<code>rake db:create </code>. The error read:

```
PG::InvalidParameterValue: ERROR:  encoding UTF8 does not match locale en_US
DETAIL:  The chosen LC_CTYPE setting requires encoding LATIN1.
: CREATE DATABASE "platform_validator_development" ENCODING = 'utf8'

```
</p>


<p>
This tends to happen when the locale isn't set before creating a database instance
inside vagrant. Digging deeper into the issue, the
<a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/8.2/static/locale.html">Postgres doc</a> states:
<blockquote><p>"Note that the locale behavior of the server is determined by the environment variables seen by the server, not by the<br/>environment of any client. Therefore, be careful to configure the correct locale<br/>settings before starting the server."</p></blockquote>
</p>


<p>
The peculiar thing about Ubuntu is that when you execute<code>sudo apt-get install postgresql libpq-dev</code>
it starts the service immediately and thus sets the locale to Latin1 (at least for the precise32 box).
Therefore, it's best practice to run
<code>sudo /usr/sbin/update-locale LANG=en_US.UTF-8 LC_ALL=en_US.UTF-8</code>
before even installing Postgres. Note, you'll need to run <code>vagrant provision </code> to
see the locale change.
</p>




<p>
Another solution, regardless of using Vagrant or not, is to update the template of
your database instance. This can be done by running the following:

```
sudo su postgres
psql

```

```
update pg_database set datistemplate=false where datname='template1';
drop database Template1;
create database template1 with owner=postgres encoding='UTF-8'
lc_collate='en_US.utf8' lc_ctype='en_US.utf8' template template0;
update pg_database set datistemplate=true where datname='template1';
```
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
