<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Motivation | Code Privy]]></title>
  <link href="http://codeprivy.com/blog/categories/motivation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://codeprivy.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-29T13:51:26-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://codeprivy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joel Taylor]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goal Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeprivy.com/blog/2014/05/27/goal-time/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-27T14:49:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://codeprivy.com/blog/2014/05/27/goal-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've spent the past five months living in Thailand. Now that I've returned
to the land of fast internet and robust coffee beans, it's time to move forward with
my Ruby on Rails agenda. To motivate myself, I've decided to set a high goal and
establish a game plan to meet that goal. As a freelancer, it's my duty to self-motivate
and challenge myself to become a better developer. There's a lot of directions to
be taken in the world of web development and goals will help to choose a path instead
of being scattered in numerous technologies with zero mastery.</p>




<h3>The goal</h3>


<p><a href="http://hashrocket.com/">Hashrocket</a> doesn't know it yet but I'm
going to be an apprentice with them in the near future.</p>




<h3>The reason</h3>


<p>They're a progressive company and are the type of team I can see myself in.
They subscribe to agile methodologies and practice pair-programming. It's a place
where I know I'd be challenged, taught, humbled, and involved in some cutting edge
development. A major spotlight is their active contribution to the open source
community.</p>


<p>Needless to say, I'm a fan.</p>




<h3>The plan</h3>




<p>Hashrocket provides the following requirements for an apprentice:</p>




<ul>
  <li>Passion for developing excellent software</li>
  <li>Basic knowledge of Ruby and Rails</li>
  <li>Enthusiasm about pairing and other Agile practices</li>
  <li>You MUST be able to work full-time at one of our offices</li>
</ul>




<p>Special consideration is given to those who:</p>




<ul>
  <li>Experience test driving application development</li>
  <li>Previous consulting experience</li>
  <li>Open source contributions</li>
  <li>Familiarity with Vim</li>
  <li>Agile (especially pair-programming) experience</li>
</ul>




<p>After finding out all I could about the apprenticeship I came across a
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SGzB-LOwEmQ">video,</a> by Hashrocket, stating
that all employees see the applications and if you're declined they'll tell you
why. They welcome people to improve and submit applications again - I've already
reasoned that I'll be submitting till I get accepted.</p>




<p>Here is what I'll be doing in the next couple weeks before I submit my application:</p>


<ul>
  <li>Read a new book each week (those related to Ruby, Rails, Agile development, etc)</li>
  <li>Devote at least 5 hours a week to an open source project</li>
  <li>Develop a CMS - one from scratch and another using open source resources</li>
  <li>Develop a personal site to represent myself</li>
  <li>Develop an application that makes use of APIs</li>
  <li>Use Vim to develop from here on</li>
</ul>




<p>I should probably stock up on coffee.</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
